# Sjoerd Vink

Cambridge, MA | s.a.vink@uu.nl | +1 (339) 223-1691 | Website | LinkedIn | Github

## **Summary**

My research focuses on developing computational techniques and interfaces that enable professionals to explore multivariate networks and identify valuable insights. By creating systems that facilitate dynamic exploration and interaction with these networks, my work aims to support users in uncovering hidden patterns, relationships, and trends that might otherwise remain obscured.

#### Education

Utrecht University, PhD in Computer ScienceSept 2024 – PresentUtrecht University, MS in Data-Science2023 - 2024University of Wisconsin-Madison, Exchange ProgramFall 2022Utrecht University, BS in Information Science2020 – 2023

#### Experience

#### **Doctoral Researcher**, Tufts University – Medford, MA (USA)

September 2024 – Present

- Conducting research in Prof. Dr. Remco Chang's Visual Analytics Lab (VALT).
- Advancing the field of visual analytics with a focus on graph exploration, data analysis, and interface development.
- Collaborating on cutting-edge techniques to enhance human-data interaction through visualization tools.

#### **Data Scientist**, GraphPolaris – Utrecht (Netherlands)

April 2023 – Present

- VC-backed start-up dedicated to pioneering advancements in graph analytics and visualization techniques.
- Selected as one of the few pioneering startups for a prestigious investment by the Dutch Research Council (NWO), with a team of engineers and scientists to advance the frontier of graph analytics.
- Played a crucial role in executive decision-making for ideation and strategy, directly contributing to the company's product development and market leadership, by aiding the CEO in steering product functionality and strategic direction.

#### Visiting Researcher, Tufts University – Medford, MA (USA)

April 2024 - July 2024

• Thesis on Automated Design of Network Visualizations under Prof. Dr. Remco Chang.

#### **Software Engineer**, Freelance – Utrecht (Netherlands)

2020 - 2023

- Developed web-applications tailored to the unique needs of local businesses.
- Provided maintenance and support services guaranteeing optimal performance and functionality.

### **Awards and Leadership**

**Financial Times**, Top 500 most talented people under the age of 30 in the field of technology.

2024

## **Teaching**

**INFOB2WT Web Technology**, Assisted in a bachelor's course in web technology at the computer-science department – Utrecht University

Spring 2023

# **Technical Skills**

Programming: Python, R, JavaScript, Typescript, Go, SQL, HTML/CSS

**Areas of expertise:** Data-Science, Machine-Learning, Deep-Learning, ML Operations, Web Development, Cloud, Big Data, Visualization, Data Mining, Time Series, NLP, Ontologies

**Technologies:** Git, SQL, NoSQL, Graph, AWS, Docker, RabbitMQ, Pandas, SK-Learn, Keras, TensorFlow, React, D3, Node, Express, Covalent

# Languages

Dutch (native), English (fluent)